

JOSE ESCARRAMAN

Statistician and Data Analyst

Granada, Spain \cdot +39 351 636 5809 Josegabriel.escarraman@gmail.com GitHub \cdot Linked-In \cdot Joseescarraman.com

About me

I'm an analyst and researcher with a strong focus on data analysis applied to social issues, health, and demographics. My background in Economics and Statistics, along with my experience in the public sector and clinical research, has made me a versatile professional capable of tackling complex challenges from different angles. I am proactive, responsible, and creative, characteristics that allow me to adapt to diverse environments and find innovative solutions.

Experience

Intern/Thesis Student

Hematology Unit of Sant'Orsola Polyclinic

Feb 2024 - July 2024

I tested the efficacy of therapy alternatives for multiple myeloma patients using statistical inference. I gained practical skills in handling clinical and genetic data, managing databases, and performing survival analysis.

Junior Analyst

Ministry of Economy, Planning and Development of the Dominican Republic Feb 2021 – Aug 2022

I Managed and interpreted data using statistical software to create reports, dashboards, maps, and articles that helped with the decision-making process in the institution. I worked on several research projects related to vulnerable regions of the country.

Research Project Assistant

Grupo Línea Base and USAID

Sep 2020 - Dic 2020

I was a technical assistant for a social research project on vulnerabilities in Dominican educational centers during the Covid-19 pandemic.

Education

Master in Statistical Sciences

University of Bologna, Italy September 2022 – July 2024 Health and Population Analytics Path.

Bachelor in Economics

Instituto Tecnológico de Santo Domingo (INTEC) November 2017 – April 2021 Graduated Summa Cum Laude.

Software Skills

• Python

• R

• SQL

• QGIS

• SAS

• Power BI